Register of the Tracy Barrett Kittredge Papers, 1910-1957
Hoover Institution Archives
Tracy Barrett Kittredge Papers,
1910-1957
60017
Hoover Institution Archives
51 manuscript boxes, 6 envelopes (21.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, writings, notes, and clippings, relating to the Commission for Relief in Belgium, 1914-1924; the Paris Peace Conference, 1919; the controversy between Admiral W. S. Sims and Secretary of the Navy Josephus Daniels, 1919-1920; the League of Red Cross Societies, 1920-1931; and American naval operations in World War II. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Kittredge, Tracy Barrett
Access
Collection open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1891 Born, Baker, Oregon
1914-17 Member and director, Educational Fund, Commission for Relief in Belgium
1917-19 Staff of Admiral William S. Sims, United States Naval Headquarters in Europe
1919 Staff, Supreme Economic Council, Paris Peace Conference
1920-31 Staff, League of Red Cross Societies
1921 Author, Certain Naval Lessons of the Great War
1931-42 Assistant Director, Social Sciences Division, Rockefeller Foundation, European Office, Paris
1942-46 Staff of Admiral Harold R. Stark, American Naval Headquarters, London
1946-54 Senior Naval member, Historical Section, Joint Chiefs of Staff
1946 Author, U.S.-British Naval Cooperation
Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948.; League of Red Cross Societies.; Sims, William Sowden, 1858-1936.; United States. Navy--Officers.
- Manuscript History of the Commission for Relief in Belgium (copy 2 in Box 52) (Box 1-2)
- Drafts of the History of the Commission for Relief in Belgium (Box 3-4)
- Reports, memoranda, and correspondence relating to the Commission for Relief in Belgium (Box 5)
- Reports, memoranda, and correspondence relating to the Commission for Relief in Belgium (Box 6)
- Letters of gratitude from the Provinces
- Postcards (47) (Box 7)
- Biographical notes on Herbert Hoover
- Belgian passport, passes, and commissions
- Newspaper clippings and printed matter
- Childhood; Oxford and early essays (Box 8)
- Early work, early studies and reading lists, 1912-1914
- Navy records concerning U.S. Naval forces in the Atlantic and German submarine strength, (two folders), 1917-1918 (Box 9)
- Letters from Professors Morse, Stephens, Teggart, Scholz
- Correspondence with John R. Rathon, Editor of the Providence Journal, about navy article and editorials, 1920 (Box 10)
- Records of the U.S. Navy, London, Papers concerning the Sims-Daniels controversy. Records of the Senate Investigating Committee, 1917-1919
- Records of the U.S. Navy, London, Papers concerning the Sims-Daniels controversy. Records of the Senate Investigating Committee, 1917-1919 (Box 11-12)
- Papers concerning Certain Naval Lessons of the Great War, published by Doubleday, Doran, 1921 (Box 12-15)
- Early naval papers concerning the Newport Naval War College while Admiral Sims was its head and T. B. Kittredge was working for him, 1919-1921 (Box 16)
- Papers concerning League of Red Cross Societies, 1921-1930
- Papers concerning League of Red Cross Societies, 1921-1930 (Box 17-18)
- Papers and letters, Rockefeller Foundation (Box 19)
- Letters, London, 1942-1946
- Letters returned from London, (Feis, Robert Sherwood, Samual Morrison, etc.), 1946-1953
- Letters, 1953-1957 (Box 20)
- Various social letters, liaison activity, London
- Text - "The Present Situation, Organization and Program of the Free French Movement," by T. B. Kittredge
- T. B. Kittredge's notes on French affairs, 1941-1942 (Box 21)
- T. B. Kittredge's notes and references - relations with Vichy 1952 review panel on the rearmament of the Free French Forces in World War II. Paper by Marcel Vigneras
- T. B. Kittredge's notes on relations with the French, 1940-1941
- T. B. Kittredge's notes on Proces du Marechal Petain, 1945
- T. B. Kittredge's text and working papers of U.S.-British Naval Relations, Sections I, III
- report of T. B. Kittredge on visits to England. Cooperation of U.S. and British Historical Services, 1949 (Box 22)
- Letters and documents. Netherlands State Institute for War Documentation, Amsterdam, Meeting, "World War II in the West" (including a history of German concentration camps), 1950
- T. B. Kittredge's publications and lectures, including those at Air War College, Maxwell Air Force Base, (copies), 1951
- Texts and letters in regard to publication in U.S. News and World Report of T. B. Kittredge's "U.S. Defense Policy and Strategy,", 1941 (Box 23)
- T. B. Kittredge's obituary from the New York Times
- Restricted files not to be looked at until after the death of Admiral Stark and Mrs. Kittredge
- Restricted files note to be looked at until after the death of Admiral Stark and Mrs. Kittredge (Box 24-26)
- Volumes of T. B. Kittredge's Review Of National Defense Policy And Strategy and typed chapters of the same. Also Administrational History, U.S Naval Forces In Europe, 1940-1946 (Box 27-31)
- Draft chapters and working notes (Box 32-34)
- Military strategy between the war, chronology (Box 35)
- American Commission to Negotiate Peace, 1919
- Notes and text, "Unconditional surrender to the Peace Conference," T. B. Kittredge's files, 1918-1919
- Working notes and references
- Notes and quotations, inter-war period
- Notes on Organization Joint Board
- Parts of chapters found in files unattached
- Notes on post-war planning, 1943
- Free French notes
- T. B. Kittredge's quotations and notes, 1945
- Memorandum and papers concerning Russia (Box 36)
- Chronological notes and quotations on aid to Russia, 1941 December 28 - 1942 July
- T. B. Kittredge's notes with references to Russia, convoys, global strategy, 1942
- Quotations from Hancock
- Letters and reports on food mission to Japan, 6 folders, 1947
- Letters and reports on food mission to Japan, 6 folders, 1947 (Box 37)
- Memorandum and references, military cooperation with Latin American Republics, Inter-American Defense Board, 1941 December-1942 February
- Correspondence with friends from Commission for Relief in Belgium, including Mrs. Hoover, Millard Shaler, Perrin Galpin
- Letters to and from Admiral Stark (Box 38)
- Letters to and from Admiral Bradley Fiske including one from Admiral Harry E. Yarnell (then captain), 1920-1921
- Personal letters in regard to C.R.B., including Perrin Galpin
- Erlich folder - not to be opened until his death
- A. Herbert Roskinski's "Halder" text, also Roskinski's Evolution Of Sea Power
- J. R. N. Butler, editor, United Kingdom Military Service, Grand Strategy, T. B. Kittredge's reviews of manuscript (Box 39)
- Letters and reports concerning review panel on Dr. Forest Pogue's "The Supreme Command," T. B. Kittredge's extensive criticism, Office of the Chief of Military History Kent Green field, 1951 June
- Political Warfare Executive, 1944 (Box 40)
- Restricted
  - Part I: Pre-Belligerency
    - Chapter I: Rearmament and Foreign Aid Prior to Lend Lease
    - Chapter II: War Plans and Emergency Preparation
    - Chapter III: The Army and Lend-Lease Operations in 1941
  - Part II: Rearmament of the French Metropolitan Forces
  - Part I: The Rearmament of the French North African Forces (Box 41)
- Copy no. 12, Office of the U.S. Naval Attaché, American Embassy, London, England, 1939-1946
- Comnaveu Historical Monograph Operation Neptune. Naval Aspects of Operation Overlord. U.S. Naval Participation in the Planning, Preparation and Conduct of Cross-Channel Operations. Prepared by Lt. Comdr. TH. MacBride, USNR
- Working notes, drafts, and partial chapters of T. B. Kittredge's "Global Strategy Policy" (Box 42-45)
- Notes, "Global Strategy Policy" (Box 46)
- Pearl Harbor Inquiry, summaries of reports
- Pearl Harbor study, quotations and notes
- Letters and reports of conversations in London about deGaulle's visit to Washington and North African landings, Also letter from Commander Knox and report on organization of Office of War Information, 1942-1943
- Activities of Intelligence Section, London, 1942-1943 (Box 47)
- Letters and documents, Naval Staff Talks (Admiral Bellairs, Historical Section, Admiralty and T. B. Kittredge, Historical Section, Joint Chiefs of Staff)
- T. B. Kittredge's Naval Orders, 1917-1957
- Correspondence with Eleanor Hayden (later Mrs. Tracy B. Kittredge), 1921
- Correspondence, A-J, 1940-1957 (Box 48)
- Correspondence, K-R, 1940-1957 (Box 49)
- Correspondence, S-Z, 1940-1957 (Box 50)
- Clippings, circa 1910-1930
- Clippings and printed matter, circa 1910-1930 (Box 51)
- Manuscript History of the Commission for Relief in Belgium, Copy 2 (Box 52)
- Declassified U.S. and British government records, 1917-1954
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1917-1954 (Reading room workstation)